Lorwin, Val Additional Papers 5716
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Val Lorwin Additional Papers
1951-1982
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Lorwin, Val
5716
8 cubic feet
8 linear ft.
Papers (documents).
These records include constitutions, proceedings, financial records, lodge books, and other items.
3338533
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, October 24, 2013
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 28, 2019
Biographical / Historical
The Ladies' Society of the Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen was recognized as an auxiliary of the Brotherhood at its second biennial convention in 1890. The Ladies' Society was organized "for the purpose of rendering assistance, encouraging the Brotherhood...in its good work, extending the hand of Charity, helping each other in time of need, and elevating our social and intellectual standing. It is also the aim of the Society to cultivate a spirit of harmony, to promote sociability, and to draw into friendly and affectionate relationship the lady members of the families of the Brotherhood."
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5028: Val Lorwin Collection of International Confederation of Free Trade Unions Documents
Economic history -- Study and teaching; International labor activities; Lorwin, Val R. (Val Rogin), 1907-
3338533
- Important documents to President Shaft (Box 1, Folder 1)
- VRL - Letters In 1965 Corres. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- VRL - Letters Out 1965 Corres. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- correspondence 1966 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Corres 1967 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- correspondence 1968 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- The Everyday File - Alphabetical Files (Box 1, Folder 7)
- VRL - JM Movement file (Box 1, Folder 8)
- AHA - Correspondence. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Price - AHA - Corres. (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Ford MS revision 1958 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Labor and Economic Development in France Draft 1957 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Journal of modern History, The University of Wisconsin, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Val Lorwin Oct 16, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- CRISP (Box 1, Folder 14)
- SED - General (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Size and Democracy - R. Dahl (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Duveau (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Mazlish (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Val Lorwin (Box 1, Folder 19)
- SFAS - Ann Arbor, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- VRL - Working-Class Politics and Economic Development in W. Europe (Box 1, Folder 21)
- ISSC July, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- MAAND (Box 1, Folder 23)
- VRL: Factoren Van Conflict en Foctoren Van Samenorighe (Box 1, Folder 24)
- VRL - Arbeidersorganisaties en Politiek in Belgie en in Frankrijk (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Opera VRL (Box 1, Folder 26)
- J.E.H. (Box 1, Folder 27)
- BEL, Lux, Amox, Enc. (Box 1, Folder 28)
- U of Lyon Lectures (Box 1, Folder 29)
- U.S. Labor Unions and Political Action (Box 1, Folder 30)
- VRL - Conflict and Compromise in Belgian Politics (Box 1, Folder 31)
- VRL - Articles II (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Reviews, FLM (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Modern France (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Val Lorwin (Box 1, Folder 35)
- CRISP (Box 1, Folder 36)
- SSRC - SED (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Univ. Gov. (Box 1, Folder 38)
- VAL - Curriculum Vitae (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Curr. Vitae - V.L. (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Empl. Prot. (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Publishers (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Agriculture (Box 2, Folder 3)
- C. Tilly + R. tilly (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Friesland (Box 2, Folder 5)
- econ. Hist. assn. (Box 2, Folder 6)
- NRA (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Encyclopedia Britannica (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Syndicalism - ESS (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Touraine (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Cha, Toronto June, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Reader - General (Box 2, Folder 12)
- VRL - What Does DeGaulle Really Want? (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Socialisme, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- WPSA (Box 2, Folder 15)
- bobbs Mellill-AHA (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Kassalow, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Vermang (Box 2, Folder 18)
- I.L.O. - corr. (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Int. Enc. Soc. Sci. (Box 2, Folder 20)
- N.Y., D.C, committee. (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Bad Hom. T (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Position Paper (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Project (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Sed - Misc. (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Austria (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Belgium (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Netherlands (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Iceland (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Switzerland (Box 2, Folder 30)
- B.H. 2 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Casbs, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Lorwin (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Bureaucracy (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Bureaucracy (Box 2, Folder 35)
- bibliography (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Glossary (Box 2, Folder 37)
- readings (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Myers - Ch. X (Box 2, Folder 39)
- SED (Box 2, Folder 40)
- Retz (Box 2, Folder 41)
- Willesden (Box 2, Folder 42)
- Rocked, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 43)
- CHA (Box 2, Folder 44)
- Cont'd Teaching (Box 2, Folder 45)
- CISH AHA (Box 3, Folder 1)
- SSRC - Correspondence. (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Interest Groups (Box 3, Folder 3)
- AAPSA, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- France - French Original (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Finland - Chap. (Box 3, Folder 6)
- N.O.R. Draft 1982 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Norway (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Dorsey contents (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Landes - Dorsey (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Browns - May, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Comp. Pols. (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Belgian Ms. (Box 3, Folder 13)
- "All colors," 1959, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Corr. - 1977-3-To Write (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Letters, IN (Box 3, Folder 16)
- corr., 1969 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- RE VRL in MAAND, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Holland (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Segmented Pluralism (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Book II - Corr. (Box 3, Folder 21)
- United Kingdom - Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Belgium - Draft Chapter (Box 3, Folder 23)
- From AC, VL (Box 3, Folder 24)
- ford Foundation - corr. (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Bellagio (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Publishers (Box 3, Folder 27)
- OK Leroy - Data (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Australia - corr. (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Canada - Draft chapter (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Canada - Chapter comment (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Canada - corr. (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Corr. - Denmark (Box 3, Folder 33)
- Denmark - Ch. Comment (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Denmark Draft Chapter (Box 3, Folder 35)
- Finland - Draft Chapter (Box 3, Folder 36)
- Germany - chap. Comment (Box 3, Folder 37)
- Germany correspondence (Box 3, Folder 38)
- Israel - Draft Ch. (Box 3, Folder 39)
- Israel - Chapter Comment (Box 3, Folder 40)
- Israel - Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 41)
- Xerox - Ireland Feb 1982 (Box 3, Folder 42)
- Italy - chapter comment (Box 3, Folder 43)
- Italy correspondence (Box 3, Folder 44)
- Italy - Draft Ch. (Box 3, Folder 45)
- Japan - Draft Ch. (Box 3, Folder 46)
- Japan - Ch. Comment (Box 3, Folder 47)
- Japan - Corr. (Box 3, Folder 48)
- Finland Corr. (Box 3, Folder 49)
- Norway - final (Box 3, Folder 50)
- Nor. Corr., Materials (Box 3, Folder 51)
- France (Box 3, Folder 52)
- France - Draft chapter (Box 3, Folder 53)
- Bibliog. (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Lorwin Materials (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Australia - Draft chap. (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Broken English (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Proudhon 442 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Bits Open Fields (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Bits (Box 4, Folder 7)
- BITS (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Term Papers Instructions 454 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Alice Nov, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Alice, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- England - Alice Corr. (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Alice H. Cook et al. (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Equal Pay (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Early Drafts (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Job Eval - Text (Box 4, Folder 16)
- V-VI - Data (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Unions + Women - Discrimination Male Psych (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Sex - Class (Box 4, Folder 19)
- SW - Den - Draft chapter (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Women and Trade Unions (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Working Copy - Sweden (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Sweden - chap. Comment (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Sweden correspondence. (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Press clippings (Box 4, Folder 25)
- ford foundation (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Daalder (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Dahl (Box 4, Folder 28)
- Sed VRL Lorwin (Box 4, Folder 29)
- SR (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Denmark (Box 4, Folder 31)
- Germany (Box 4, Folder 32)
- CUNY - Slight aug, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 33)
- CUNY (Box 4, Folder 34)
- Belgium (Box 4, Folder 35)
- Stanford Press (Box 4, Folder 36)
- SED (Box 4, Folder 37)
- Corr. Pre-1964 (Box 4, Folder 38)
- The Early Trade Unions (Box 4, Folder 39)
- Labor Issues Alphabetical Order (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Lorwin Corr. (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Lorwin Issues (Box 5, Folder 3)
- BITS (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Simon - Austr. (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Report to contributors (Box 6, Folder 3)
- O'Sullivan July 1951 Affidavits (Box 6, Folder 4)
- State Department Loyalty Security Board In Re: Val Lorwin (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Pre-1935 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Can - Corr. After May, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- V. Lorwin (Box 6, Folder 8)
- OFCL Corres. (Box 6, Folder 9)
  Scope and Contents
  Incomplete O'Sullivan; complete documents are @ 21 E 40 St NYC
- HWM (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Sen. Hennings (Box 6, Folder 11)
- VRL Circa 1935 (Box 6, Folder 12)
- CUD (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Lectures, Exams (Box 6, Folder 14)
- VRL - Case - 1955 (Box 6, Folder 15)
- SACB (Box 6, Folder 16)
- Post - 1941 (Box 6, Folder 17)
- AFGE - UFWA (Box 6, Folder 18)
- KAOW - PAN (Box 6, Folder 19)
- Socialist Party (Box 6, Folder 20)
- McCarthy (Box 6, Folder 21)
- Lorwin Case - Materials (Box 6, Folder 22)
- Kefauver (Box 6, Folder 23)
- Statements + Marshall (Box 6, Folder 24)
- count records (Box 6, Folder 25)
- Misc. (Box 6, Folder 26)
- Case, Aftermath (Box 6, Folder 27)
- Misc. Notes - Case (Box 6, Folder 28)
- Span. Aid comm. (Box 6, Folder 29)
- Press, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 30)
- Major Re: Case (Box 6, Folder 31)
- State Department Investigation (Box 6, Folder 32)
- Lorwin (Box 6, Folder 33)
- Ind. Empl. Review Board (Box 6, Folder 34)
- Corr. Clippings, etc. Loaned El. Bontecov (Box 6, Folder 35)
- V Lorwin corr. (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Opera VRL (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Comp. Pol., 1971 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- All Colors (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Vermang (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Sweden, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  Aug. 19
- U.K. With S.B. Comments, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  Aug
- O.K. (Box 7, Folder 8)
- U.K. final Sept 25, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Ireland - Correspondence (Box 7, Folder 10)
- MAAND - CRISP (Box 7, Folder 11)
- BK II - Outlines Billy's, Inc. (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Den May, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Leroy July, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Denm. (Box 7, Folder 15)
- France - Corr. (Box 7, Folder 16)
- CRISP, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 17)
- CUNY (Box 7, Folder 18)
- US - Corr. Curriculum vitae (Box 7, Folder 19)
- US Chapter Comment (Box 7, Folder 20)
- U.K. (Box 7, Folder 21)
- AHA, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 22)
- TLS (Box 7, Folder 23)
- Misc. (Box 7, Folder 24)
- France (Box 7, Folder 25)
- S Kramer - Gelb. Neo - Soc. (Box 7, Folder 26)
  Feb
- Windmuller, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 27)
- McRae, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 28)
- Misc. - Europe (Box 7, Folder 29)
- Master - 2 (Structures) (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Master - 2 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- VRL Articles (Box 8, Folder 3)
- VIII - P-T Master (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Ch. 9 Safety (Box 8, Folder 5)
- chap X conclusion (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Lorwin, Till-Retz, Cook Ch. 8 May 20, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Extra Copies - 5 (c. Barg.) (Box 8, Folder 8)
- V - C.B Materials (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Master - 4 (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Ribbon - 4 (Training) (Box 8, Folder 11)
- IV - Draft (Box 8, Folder 12)
- Materials for Draft - Voc. Training (Box 8, Folder 13)
- Fix 1846 (Box 8, Folder 14)
- Extra Copies - 4 (Box 8, Folder 15)
- Master - 5 (Coll. Bargaining) (Box 8, Folder 16)
- Chap V - CIB Action July 20, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 17)
- Ribbon - 3 (Education) (Box 8, Folder 18)
- Ch. I - Master (Box 8, Folder 19)
- Extra Copies - 2 (Struct.) (Box 8, Folder 20)
- I - Intro Master (Box 8, Folder 21)
- Ribbon - 1 (Intro) (Box 8, Folder 22)
- chapters Dec 18, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 23)
- Bouquet File (Box 8, Folder 24)
- Cook corr. - Jan. - Aug., 1980 (Box 8, Folder 25)
- German Marshall Fund (Box 8, Folder 26)
- Alice Sept., 1980 (Box 8, Folder 27)
- Cook - Corr., 1978 (Box 8, Folder 28)
- Project Correspondence Alice Cook (Box 8, Folder 29)
- 2 - Planning (Box 8, Folder 30)
- file (Box 8, Folder 31)
- All Colors (Box 8, Folder 32)
- correspondence (Other files also cover this period), 1958-1963 (Box 8, Folder 33)
- Calvert (Box 8, Folder 34)
- Opp. Corr. (Box 8, Folder 35)
- Bel. - Bureaucracy (Box 8, Folder 36)
- Bel. - Bureaucracy (Box 8, Folder 36)